Most health insurances do
not cover maternity related medical expenses
like delivery expenses, new
born baby cover or vaccination
charges. If you are looking for such health
insurance which covers all these
charges then stay with
this video and at the end of the video
I will also tell you
which is the best plan among all these plans for you.
Hello friends, I am Ashutosh Shukla,
Certified Financial Gold Planner, MP
Registered Mutual Fund Distributor,
Insurance and Mutual Fund Expert. If you
want any free first consultation related to health insurance, life term insurance or mutual fund, then you
can WhatsApp on the number given below. Let's
start the video.
[Music]
This plan is only maternity coverage
specification, hence we will only
talk about those things which are
related to maternity,
treatment, domestic treatment, no claim
bonus. We will not talk about all these in this video. The
detailed videos of all these plans
are available in the health insurance playlist of our channel, where you can
go and check them.  First of all,
we will talk about Star Comprehensive Plan.
In this plan, maternity feature
is built-in. Talking about the waiting period in this plan, there is a
waiting period of 24 months.
For maternity coverage,
normal caesarean section delivery is covered in this plan.
If we talk about coverage, in a policy of Rs 5 lakh,
charges of Rs 15,000 will be covered for normal delivery. In a policy of Rs 7.5 lakh,
charges of up to Rs 25,000 will be covered.
For normal delivery, C-section charges of
Rs 40,000 will be covered and for newborn baby,
charges of Rs 1 lakh will be covered. If we
talk about a policy of Rs 10 lakh, charges of up
to Rs 30,000 will be covered for normal delivery and
charges of up to Rs 50,000 will be covered for C-section delivery and
charges of Rs 1 lakh will be covered for newborn baby.
Talking about a policy of Rs 50 lakh to Van Kar, charges of Rs
50,000 for normal delivery and 30 second
delivery  Charges up to ₹15 lakh will be
covered and for newborn baby,
charges up to ₹1 lakh will be covered.
Talking about vaccination,
vaccination coverage will be available for newborn baby up to one year onwards, in
which charges of ₹5 lakh to ₹25
lakh will be covered for the policy with the policy.
Medical expenses from maternity to delivery and post hospital will
not be applicable. The
maternity cover in all the three plans will be available for delivery and
termination. The
maternity coverage in all the three plans is
dependent on their time.
In the Silver plan, charges up to ₹40000 for ₹500 crore
and up to ₹60000 in the ₹7.5 lakh policy will be
covered.
In the Gold plan, charges up to ₹70000 for ₹10 lakh policy will be covered and
charges up to ₹
15 lakh policy will be covered.  For the Platinum plan, charges up to Rs 1 lakh will be
covered. For the
30 leg and 50 leg
policy, charges up to Rs 75,000 will be covered. For the 30 leg and 50 leg policy, charges up to Rs 1 lakh will be
covered. Talking about vaccinations, all the
vaccinations of the newborn baby till 1 year onwards will be covered. There is
a list of these in which BCG, OPV,
OPT, Hepatitis B, HIV, ROI, MR,
Typhoid and Hepatitis B
vaccinations will be covered. Talking about the Platinum plan,
charges up to Rs 1 lakh will be covered for maternity, in which there will be
domestic and well as worldwide coverage
excluding Russia and Canada, meaning if
you want to go out of India for delivery, then you
can deliver in any other country except Russia and Canada. The
next plan is ICICI Lombard Health
Advantage. Maternity is not inbuilt in this plan,
rather you
can get it in your plan by paying an extra premium as a rider.
This cover is for the age from 18 years to 45 years onwards.  This plan will be
available only for Rs. 10 lakh, for which you will have to pay a
premium of three years upfront. A
waiting period of 9 months will be applicable in this plan for delivery.
For maternity cover, you will be
available benefits up to 10% of your sum assured,
which will be available for a maximum of Rs. 10 lakh
and a maximum of up to two deliveries.
Apart from maternity cover,
your maternity cover for the new born will be available, which will be a
maximum of Rs. 10 lakh. The
next plan is Care Joy Today. This plan has an
inbuilt maternity cover. Care Today is
similar to ICICI Health Advantage,
which has a waiting period of 9 months. You will have to pay a
premium of three years upfront for delivery
and the maternity
cover will be available only for up to 45 years.
For maternity cover, charges of up to Rs. 35 thousand will be available in a policy of Rs. 3 lakh
and charges of up to Rs. 250 thousand will be available in a policy of Rs. 5 lakh.
New born baby  Talking about the cover,
charges up to Rs 30,000 will be covered in a 3 lakh policy and
up to Rs 50,000 in a 5 lakh policy.
Newborn baby
coverage will be available for 90 days.
After that, you can pay the applicable premium and get a premium
in your plan. It is
very difficult because every
individual has a retirement age. For example, there is a
two-year waiting period
for maternity. Similarly, ICICI Health Advantage and
Carjoy Today have a waiting period of only 9 months,
but the 3-year
premium in these has to be paid upfront.
If you want to know which plan will be
more suitable for you, you can book
a free help consultation by WhatsApping the number given below.
If you have
any doubts related to health insurance,
please let us know by commenting below. And
if you liked the video, please like.
Thank you
[Music]